Guide to The Leo Deaner Radical Left-Wing Publications collection, 1890-2017 LAC0011
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Pamphlets by topic, 1890-2017; Series 3
  - Events and issues, 1924-2013; Series 3 Subseries 4
    - Events and Issues, 1943-2009; Series 3 Subseries 4 (Box 122, Folder 3)
      Civil Liberties in the U.S.A.: a short History of the Origin and Defense of the Bill of Rights by S. Small McCarthy on Trial: an Account of an Investigation into the Activities of Senator Joseph R. McCarthy conducted by a New York Trade Union Veterans Committee … Edited by Albert E. Kahn; Behind the Bars for the First Amendment Written by Several of the Defendants on Behalf of the Committee of First Amendment Defendants; Toward Unity in Defense Against Repression: 21st Annual Conference Journal, 1971 Published by Los Angeles Committee for Defense of the Bill of Rights; Alliance/Citizens Alert Civil Suit and Complete Text of the Cook County Grand Jury Report on Police Slaying in Chicago Published by Citizens Alert-Litigation Fund; Staying Free by Shutting the Fuck Up! By Harold H. Thompson; Cointelpro-Domestic Subversive Warfare: the Case of Clark, et al. versus the United States Published by Committee for the Suit Against Government Misconduct; 22nd Annual Report of the Subversive Activities Control Board, Fiscal Year ended June 30, 1972, Published by USGPO; FBI v. the First Amendment by Richard Criley Published by First Amendment Foundation; Radical Defense Handbook Published by Movement Liberation Front; When in Court Defend Yourself by Larry Lockshin Published by Coalition to Defend the October 20th Freedom Fighters
    - Events and Issues, 1967-1975; Series 3 Subseries 4 (Box 122, Folder 4)
      Contents in folder include publications about Community Organizing
      ACORN Published by Arkansas Community Organizations for Reform Now; WelfareL Why Workers Need it, How Billionaires Get It by Elizabeth Ross; Precinct Organizing: a Grass Roots Handook Published by People's Party; Price of Food Published by Political Education Project (Political Education Project Report no. 1); Energy Crisis Published by Political Education Project (Political Education Project Report no. 2); Who Pays Taxes Published by Political Education Project (Political Education Project Report no. 3); Our Taxes for Torture? Published by Political Education Project (Political Education Project Report no. 4); Where its at: a Research Guide for Community Organizing by Jill Hamberg; White Lightening: a Revolutionary Organization Dedicated to Serving the People no. 21 (November 1973)-no. 22 (December 1973)
    - Events and Issues, 1977-1980; Series 3 Subseries 4 (Box 122, Folder 5)
      Contents in folder include publications about Tenants Rights
      Handbook on Tenants' Rights: How to Delay and Eviction, Get your Deposit Back, Get Repairs made and More Published by Peoples Law School; Tenants' Rights Published by Community Education Program, Asian Law Caucus; Tenant Handbook, Updated 1977 Published by San Francisco Tenants Union; Tenant Handbook, Updated 1978 Published by San Francisco Tenants Union; Tenants Rights Handbook Updated July 1981 Published by San Francisco Tenants Union; Moderate Rent Control: the Experiences of U.S. Cities Published by Conference on Alternative State and Local Policies (Public Policy Report 3)
    - Events and Issues, 1970-2011; Series 3 Subseries 4 (Box 123, Folder 1)
      Contents in folder include:publications about Women's Liberation
      Political Economy of Women's Liberation by Margaret Benston Reprinted from Monthly Review, September 1969; Not just Suffrage, but Equality Pledge California Women by Mary Lou Lyon; Rape, Racism, and the White Women's Movement: an Answer to Susan Brownmiller by Alison Edwards, 2nd edition Published by Sojourner Truth Organization; Sisterhood is Powerful by Betsey Stone (Merit Pamphlet); Sylvia Weinstein, 1926-2001; Women and the New World; Women Fight Back by Kath Ennis Published by Women's Voice and the International Socialists; Presentations and Discussions about the Relevance of Marxism to the University Women and Feminism Issues in the Economy: Series of Talks by Union for Radical Political Economics and Union of Marxist Social Scientists; Greenham Women Against Cruise Missiles Published by Center for Constitutional Rights (Legal Educatin Pamphlet); Politica of Housework by Pat Mainardi
    - Events and Issues, 1975-2002; Series 3 Subseries 4 (Box 123, Folder 2)
      Contents in folder include:publications about Armed Struggle - USA
      Until all are Free: the Trial Statement of Ray Luc Levasseur Published by Attack International; Trial Statements of Ray Luc Levasseur; TUG no., 2 Published by New World Liberation Front; Bill & Emily Harris' Exclusive Story: Twenty Months Underground with Patty Published in New Times March 1976; Armed & Dangerous by Political Prisoner Raymond Luc Levasseur; Fire Inside by Political Prisoner Raymond Luc Leasseur
    - Events and Issues, 1975; Series 3 Subseries 4 (Box 123, Folder 3)
      Inside Story, pts. 1-2 Published as Rolling Stone Issue no. 198 (October 23, 1975) and issue no. 200 (November 20, 1975)
    - Events and issues, 1977-1997; Series 3 Subseries 4 (Box 158, Folder 1)
      Materials in this folder relate to the Global Economy: Imperialist Globalization and the Fight for a Different Future by Raymond Lotta; Yanqui Dollar The Contribution of U.S. Private Investment to Underdevelopment in Latin America; The New Imperialism by M.E. Chamberlain; The speech Nixon and Mitchell tried to ban by Ernest Mandel; Colonial Trade Unions; Anthropology and Imperialism by Kathleen Gough Aberle; Two Essays on Imperialism by E. Germain and Ernest Mandel; The Insurgent Sociologist; Colonialsim by Maia Ramnath; The Poor and the Superpoor.
    - Events and issues, 1992-1995; Series 3 Subseries 4 (Box 158, Folder 2)
      Materials in this folder relate to the Global Economy: Columbus and the New World Older; Global Interference by Tony Gilbert and Pierre Joris; Military Indoctrination and United States Imperialism by Miles Wolpin; The Average Citizen's Guide to the Multinational Corporation; Scarce Resources by Heather Dean; The Case of the People Against Standard Oil by Alan S. Miller; Facing the 1980s: New Directions in the Theory of Imperialism; Trilateral Commission: The new U.S. Imperialist World Strategy; Psychology and Imperialism.
    - Events and issues, 1927-1975; Series 3 Subseries 4 (Box 158, Folder 3)
      Materials in this folder relate to the Russian Revolution: The Platform of the Left Opposition (1927); Russia 1917-1921; Unemployed Council in St. Petersburg in 1906 by Sergei Malyshev; On the 100th Anniversary of the Jewish Labor Bund by Marvin S. Zuckerman; The October Revolution and the Trade Unions by A. Abolin; The Kronstadt Rebellion in the Soviet Union 1921; The Kronstadt Commune by Ida Mett.
    - Events and issues, 1976-1990; Series 3 Subseries 4 (Box 158, Folder 4)
      The materials in this folder relate to the Global Economy: Financial Ecological Destruction: The World Bank and the International Monetary Fund; Gulf Oil Corporation A Report; Toxic Empire; NAFTA's Broken Promises: Failure to Create U.S. Jobs; The Global Factory; Solidarity in the Heartland; A Citizen's Guide to the World Trade Organization; Expanding Empire by Vincent Copeland; Latin America and Empire Report; The Hannah Industrial Complex.
    - Events and issues, 1938-2013; Series 3 Subseries 4 (Box 163, Folder 1)
      Materials in this folder relate to Political Repression in the USA: Mothers in Exile; Smith Act Frame-Up!; Eternal Vigilance! The Story of Liberty 1937-1938; The Persecution of Oleta O'Connor Yates; The Walter-McCarran Law Threatens the Citizenship of Anna and Steve Devunich; This Man Is Sentenced to Death by the Walter-McCarran Act; The Case of Carl Marzani; Civil Rights at the Crossroads; Stop the Denaturalization of Joe Mankin; The Twelve and Youby Elizabeth Gurley Flynn; Story of the Imperial Valley by Frank Spector; If an Agent Knocks; Books on Trial by Alexander Trachtenberg; The Smith Act - A Threat to Labor by Louis Weinstock; Punishing Protest by Heidi Boghosian; the New State Repression by Ken Lawrence; A Talk on Security with J. Sakai and G20 Repression and Infiltratin in Toronto: An Interview with Mandy Hiscocks; International Labor Defender.
    - Events and issues, 1942-1994; Series 3 Subseries 4 (Box 163, Folder 2)
      Materials in this folder relate to Slavery/Civil War/Reconstruction: Pre-Civil War Black Nationalism by Bill McAdoo; the Buffalo Soldiers; Harriet Tubman Negro Soldier and Abolitionist by Earl Conrad; Abraham Lincoln A Real American by Mayor Daniel W. Hoan; Frederick Douglass by Steve Kingston; Michigan Labor and the Civil War; Black Reconstruction in South Carolina by John G. Jackson; John Brown American Martyr by Herbert Aptheker; the Heritage of the Civil War by Will Herberg; War Elections 1862-1864 by Lee Norton; Lincoln's Third Party by Elizabeth Lawson; John Brown's Raid.
    - Events and issues, 1950-1980; Series 3 Subseries 4 (Box 164, Folder 1)
      Materials in this folder relate to Political Repression: The New Right: A Growing Force in State Politics; McCarthyism in the Courts by Mel Fiske; Academic Freedom Committee of the American Civil Liberties Union; The Bill of Rights in Danger! by George Novack; Our Generation Will Not Be Silent!; Political Prisoners Issue; McCarthyism and the Big Lie by Milton Howard; Can Americans tolerate prison for ideas?; Unite to Repeal Criminal Syndicalism Law; Criminal Trials: Repression of American Radicals.
    - Events and Issues, 1920-2011; Series 3 Subseries 4 (Box 187, Folder 1)
      Content in this folder relate to the Russian Revolution
      The CNT and the Russian Revolution; The Bolshevik Revolution; Communist Morality; The Third Revolution?; Alexandra Kollontai Women Workers Struggle for Rights; Kronstadt in the Russian Revolution; Heroes of the Russian Revolution.
    - Events and Issues, 1932-1996; Series 3 Subseries 4 (Box 187, Folder 2)
      Content in this folder relate the Russian Revolution
      A Bad Business - The February Revolution in Tver; Soldiers, Peasant-Soldiers, and Peasant-WOrkers and Their Organizations in Petrograd: Ground-Level Revolution During the Early Months of 1917; Lenin and Krupskaya; Provocateurs I Have Known; Ivan Babushkin A Short Biography; Why Soviet Russia Should Be Recognized; Teh Kronstadt Revolt.
    - Events and Issues, 1978-2000; Series 3 Subseries 4 (Box 187, Folder 3)
      Content in this folder relate to Globalization
      Globalization in Our Own Front Yard; Global Village Vs. Global Pillage A One-World Strategy for Labor; Globalisation: Ten Frequently Asked Questions and Some Surprising Answers; The World Trade Organisation: Challenge to the International Labour Movement; Car Wars: The Internationalization of the Automobile Industry; Threadbare How the Rich Stitch Up the World's Rag Trade; Oppose Corporate Tyranny; Unions and Free Trade: Solidarity vs. Competition; The Japanese Economic Miracle and the Workers; NAFTA GATT and the World Trade Organization; Free Trade Organizer's Packet.
  - People, 1911-2014; Series 3 Subseries 5
    - People, 1971-1973; Series 3 Subseries 5 (Box 39, Folder 2)
      The heritage of Debs the fight against war; Pettis Perry the story of a working class leader by Richard O. Boyer; End racism & repression Angela Davis Day; Joseph Stalin dialectical and historical materialism a succinct presentation of the philosophic foundation of Marxism; Mao as a dialectician by Martin Glaberman; Stalin on strategy and tactics
    - People, 1967-1990; Series 3 Subseries 5 (Box 39, Folder 3)
      Malcolm's legacy; The coming black rebellion and the legacy of Malcolm X by Nat Weinstein, Jim Henle, & Roland Sheppard with an introduction by Kwame M.A. Somburu; Malcolm X fighter for black liberation by Joe Ryan, Nat Weinstein and Kwame M.A. Somburu; Malcolm X talks to young people a Young Socialist Pamphlet; The assassination of Malcolm X & Martin Luther King by Roland Sheppard; Two speeches by Malcolm X; Manning Marable on Malcolm X his message and meaning; Myths about Malcolm X two views: Rev. Albert Cleage and George Breitman; The Realist issue about Malcolm X No. 73 February 1967
    - People, 1969-1979; Series 3 Subseries 5 (Box 39, Folder 4)
      Malcolm X the man and his ideas by George Breitman; Two speeches by by Malcolm X; The fight to free Angela Davis its importance for the working class by Charlene Mitchell; From Joan to Angela a bitter ballad of oppression and martyrs by Bill Conway; Free Angela Davis hero of the Other America; The meaning of San Rafael by Henry Winston; Freed by the people the closing defense statement made in the Angela Davis case; Angela Davis: put people before profits; America on trail the frame up of Angela Davis; A political biography of Angela Davis
    - People, 1979-1981; Series 3 Subseries 5 (Box 65, Folder 3)
      Workers' Report on the Conditions of Labor and their Effect on Patient Care at San Francisco General Hospital, March 1979 by the Institute for the Study of Labor and Economic Crisis with the assistance of the Working Committee to Improve Hospital Services and Rebel Worker Organization [issued in Synthesis, Fall 1979]; Revolution and Intervention in Central America [issued as Contemporary Marxism, Special Emergency Issue Summer 1981]
    - People, Circa 1911-1979; Series 3 Subseries 5 (Box 65, Folder 4)
      Canton Speech with Statements to the Jury and the Court by Eugene V. Debs; Convict 9653: America's Vision Maker: Story of Eugene Victor Debs, the United States' Great Socialist Anti-Militarist by Guy A. Alfred; Deb's Treachery to the Working Class by Wm. J. Pinkerton; E.V. Debs: the Socialist Movement of his Time, its meaning for Today by James P. Cannon; Debs [advertisement for video-tape] by the American People's Historical Society
    - People, 1928-1965; Series 3 Subseries 5 (Box 65, Folder 5)
      Karl Marx: His Life and Work: Reminiscences by Paul LaFarague and Wilhelm Liebknecht; Life and Teachings of Friedrich Engles by M. J. Olgin; Karl Marx by L. Perchik; The Mark by Frederick Engels; Fourteenth of March 1883: Frederick Engels on the Death of Karl Marx; F. Engels: Articles from The Labour Standard (1881)
    - People, Circa 1932-1969; Series 3 Subseries 5 (Box 65, Folder 6)
      Struggle for State Power: Articles from Vperiod, Jue-July 1917 by Leon Trotsky, edited with an introduction by Louis C. Fraina; Leon Trotsky on Black Nationalism and Self-Determination edited by George Breitman; Trade Unions in the Epoch of Imperialist Decay by Leon Trotsky; Leon Trotsky on the Trade Unions with prefaces by Farrell Dobbs; If America Sould go Communist by Leon Trotsky; Russian Revolution by Leon Trotsky
    - People, 1937-1972; Series 3 Subseries 5 (Box 65, Folder 7)
      Russian Revolution by Rosa Luxemburg with an introduction by Bertram D. Wolfe; Rose Luxemburg a study by Tony Cliff; Junius Pamphlet: the Crisis in the German Social Democracy, February-April 1915 by Rosa Luxemburg; Reform or Revolution by Rosa Luxemburg, translated by Integer; Mass Strike, the Political Party, and the Trade Unions by Rosa Luxemburg, translated by Patrick Lavin; Martyrs of the Third International: Karl Liebknecht, Rosa Luxemburg by Leon Trotsky; Prison Letters to Sophie Liebknecht by Rosa Luxemburg; Rosa Luxemburg on the Spartacus Programme translated by Eden and Cedar Paul; Letters from Prison by Rosa Luxemburg, translated from the German by Eden and Cedar Paul; Socialism and the Churches by Rosa Luxemburg, translated from the French by Juan Punto; Rosa Luxemburg: Selections from her Works edited by Virgil J. Vogel
    - People, Circa 1980-1983; Series 3 Subseries 5 (Box 66, Folder 3)
      Translation of the first section of Traite de savoirvivre a l'usage des jeunes generations by Raoul Vaneigem [by Marlene Dixon]; Future of Women by Marlene Dixon; Basic Facts About Proposition P by Committee to Tax the Corporations; Plain Speaking: a News Journal of the Democratic Workers Party, v. 5, no. 15 (November 1/15, 1981)-v. 6, no. 1 (January 1/15, 1982)
    - People, 1978-1982; Series 3 Subseries 5 (Box 66, Folder 4)
      Quebec and the Parti Quebecois edited by Marlene Dixon and Susanne Jonas, Synthesis vol. 2, no. 4 (Fall 1978); Revolution and Intervention in Central America originally issued in Contemporary Marxism, edited by Marlene Dixon and Susanne Jonas.
    - People, Circa 1999; Series 3 Subseries 5 (Box 67, Folder 1)
      Leninism or Marxism? Or Organizational Questions of Russian Social Democracy by Rosa Luxemburg
    - People, 1919-2010; Series 3 Subseries 5 (Box 67, Folder 2)
      Anarchism: What it Really Stands for. 2nd ed. By Emma Goldman; Anarchism: What it Really Stands for by Emma Goldman and Who Was Emma Goldman? By Workers' Solidarity Movement.
    - People, Circa 1978-2016; Series 3 Subseries 5 (Box 67, Folder 3)
      Fred Newman (Philosopher) by Wikipedia; Struggle by the International Workers Party; Who's Behind the Struggle? New Alliance Party by Fred Newman; Critical Practice: the Theoretical Journal of the International Workers Party; Plan of Action – Down with Apartheid – Full Divestment Now and the Next Step by Internationalist Workers Party; Call to a National Conference to Unite the Movement Against Apartheid by International Workers Party; End Apartheid! Invest in Revolution by International Workers Party; After April 20th the Fight's not Over! By International Workers Party; Finamore is the Right Wing in S.F, Coalition by Central Los Angeles Branch of the International Workers Party; International Workers Party (Fourth International) by Political Bureau of the IWP (FI); Electoral Manifesto of the Internationalist Workers Party (Fourth International); Proposals for Action for the Coalition Against the Simpson-Mazzoli Bill; Repeal the Simpson-Rodino Act! Defend the Central American Revolution; Don't Accept Anything less than Full Divestment Now! By Internationalist Workers Party; Luchar por Nuestros Derechos! Opposition Forum by Internationalist Workers Party; Bay Area Labor and Socialist Educational Conference; Self-Defense Group Defeats Attack on Workers' Meeting in Los Angeles; Open Letter to the Internationalist Workers Party, 1/21/83 by Earl Owens; Open Letter to the Peace, Jobs, and Justice Coalition by Internationalist Workers Party; Night of Solidarity with Metropolitan Federation of Chilean Workers; Cultural Event in Solidarity with Chile; New Militant, Local 2; After April 20, What Next? By Internationalist Workers Party (FI); Telegram to the Colombian Government by Justice for the Five Colombian Trade Unionists Committee
    - People, 1934-1960; Series 3 Subseries 5 (Box 67, Folder 4)
      Lenin on Imperialism, the Eve of the Proletarian Social Revolution; Lenin on the National Liberation Movement; Lenin on Proletarian Revolution and Proletarian Dictatorship; Lenin on the Revolutionary Proletarian Party of a New Type; Lenin on the Struggle Against Revisionism; Lenin on War and Peace; Lenin in the October Revolution: Reminiscences of Participants; Lenin on the Woman in Question by Clara Zetkin
    - People, 1965-1967; Series 3 Subseries 5 (Box 67, Folder 5)
      Malcolm X on Afro-American History in International Socialist Review, March-April 1976; Malcolm X in International Socialist Review, Spring 1965
    - People, 1977-1980; Series 3 Subseries 5 (Box 67, Folder 6)
      In Defense of the Working Class by Marlene Dixon; Women in Class Struggle by Marlene Dixon; Workers' Report on the Conditions of Labor and Their Effect on Patient Care at San Francisco General Hospital by Institute for the Study of Labor and Economic Crisis; Struggle in Southern Africa by the Workers Party for Proletarian Socialism; Against Leninism by the League for Proletarian Socialism; Ugly Truth about BART by Rebel Worker Organization; Workers Speak Out by Rebel Worker Organization; Open Letter to the Mayor of San Francisco by Reel Workers Sitting-In; Stop Unin Busting! By Rebel Worker Organization; Defend the Right to Strike! By Rebel Worker Organization; Make BART Safe by Rebel Worker Organization
    - People, 1972-1978; Series 3 Subseries 5 (Box 87, Folder 1)
      Contents in folder include publications by or about Charles Loren
      Struggle for the Party: Two Lines in the Movement by Charles Loren; China's Education on the New Long March by Charles Loren; Classes in the United States: Workers Against Capitalists by Charles Loren; Anti-Marxist-Leninist Line of Progressive Labor by John Ericson and Charles Loren
    - People, 1967-1969; Series 3 Subseries 5 (Box 87, Folder 2)
      Contents in folder include publications by or about Martin Sostre
      To the Black Community: Message from Jail, an Interview with Martin Sostre; Martin Sostre in Court Edited by Bob McCubbin, Issued by the Martin Sostre Defense Committee; Mind Control of Prisoners: Come to a Meeting Saturday June 16 … [Flyer]
    - People, 1977-1983; Series 3 Subseries 5 (Box 87, Folder 3)
      Contents in folder include publications by or about Ray O. Light
      Ray O. Light Newsletter: no. 6 (March 1982), no. 14 (November 1982), no. 18 (March 1983), no. 19 (April 1983), no. 24 (September 1983), no., 26 (November 1983); Present Party-Building Movement in the USA and the Materialist Conception of History by Ray O. Light
    - People, 1935-1976; Series 3 Subseries 5 (Box 87, Folder 4)
      Contents in folder include publications by or about Marx, Engels
      Value, Price and Profit by Karl Marx, Edited by Eleanor Marx Aveling; Engels in the Struggle for Revolutionary Marxism: Speech on the Fortieth Anniversary of the Death of Friedrich Engels… August 5, 1936 by D.Z. Manuilsky; Early Development of the Family, Published by New England Free Press
    - People, 1932-1972; Series 3 Subseries 5 (Box 87, Folder 5)
      Contents in folder include publications by or about Lenin
      Paris Commune by V.I. Lenin (Little Lenin Library no. 5); Letters from Afar by V.I. Lenin (Little Lenin Library no. 8); April Conference by V.I. Lenin (Little Lenin Library no. 10); Threatening Catastrophe and How to Fight It by V.I. Lenin (Little Lenin Library no. 11); Will the Bolsheviks Retain State Power? by V.I. Lenin (Little Lenin Library no. 12); On the Eve of October by V.I. Lenin (Little Lenin Library no. 13); Young Generation by V.I. Lenin (Little Lenin Library no. 26); Lenin on the Jewish Question; Lenin Speaks to the Youth; Imperialism and the Split in Socialism by V.I. Lenin; Reminiscences of Lenin by Clara Zetkin; Teachings of Karl Marx by V.I. Lenin (Little Lenin Library)
    - People, 1932-1943; Series 3 Subseries 5 (Box 87, Folder 6)
      Contents in folder include publications by or about Stalin
      Stalin on the War and the Second Front in Europe; Lenin Heritage by Joseph Stalin; Interview with the German Author Emil Ludwig by J. Stalin; War of National Liberation: a Second Collection of the Wartime Addresses of the Soviet Premier Joseph Stalin (Little Lenin Library v. 28A); National Question and Leninism by Joseph Stalin; Road to Power by Joseph Stalin; Stalin on the New Soviet Constitution
    - People, 1927-1976; Series 3 Subseries 5 (Box 106, Folder 3)
      Contents in folder include publications by/about Kropotkin
      Appeal to the Young by P. Kropotkin; Russian Revolution & the soviet Government by Peter Kropotkin; State: its Historic Role by Peter Kropotkin; Law: the Supporter of Crime by Peter Kropotkin; Peter Kropotkin: His Federalist Ideas by Camillo Berneri; Appeal to the Young, Memorial Edition by Peter Kropotkin; Peter Kropotkin (Freedom Anarchist Pamphlets, no. 4-no. 5)
    - People, 1952-1966; Series 3 Subseries 5 (Box 106, Folder 4)
      Contents in folder include publications about Fritchman